Guide to the James Payne Alter Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence, Series I
  - General correspondence
    - V (Box 15, Folder 327)
    - Vanderbilt University Christian Association, 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 328)
    - W (Box 15, Folder 329)
    - Waters, Phil, 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 330)
    - Weber, Ted, 1940-1942 (Box 15, Folder 331)
    - Webster, John C. [see Series V. Biographical Material]
    - Weigle, Luther A., 1942 (Box 15, Folder 332)
    - Weir, John Barr, 1954-1978 (Box 15, Folder 333)
    - Welles, Jeane S., 1979 (Box 15, Folder 334)
    - Wesley Press, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 335)
    - West Charlton United Presbyterian Church, Amsterdam, NY, 1966-1974 (Box 15, Folder 336)
    - Westminster Presbyterian Church, Utica, NY, 1954-1963 (Box 15, Folder 337)
    - Westminster Presbyterian Church, Utica, NY, 1964-1981 (Box 16, Folder 338-339)
    - Wiggin and Dana: Counsellors at Law, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 340)
    - Wilson, Rev. H. R., 1970 (Box 16, Folder 341)
    - World Student Christian Federation, 1942-1944 (Box 16, Folder 342)
    - World Student Service Fund, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 343)
    - Wyon, John and Elizabeth, 1959-1976 (Box 16, Folder 344)
    - Wysham, Don and Dorie, 1976-1978 (Box 16, Folder 345)
    - Y (Box 16, Folder 346)
    - Yale Divinity School, 1941-1944, 1969-1980 (Box 16, Folder 347-348)
    - Yale University Christian Association, 1939-1945, 1969-1982 (Box 16, Folder 349-350)
    - Yale University Class of 1940, 1940-1983 (Box 16, Folder 351)
    - Yale University - Correspondence with classmates, 1940-1942 (Box 16, Folder 352-354)
    - Yale University - miscellaneous correspondence (Box 16, Folder 355)
    - Z (Box 16, Folder 356)
    - Zerby, Raymond, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 357)
    - first name only (Box 16, Folder 358-359)
- Writings, Series II
  - Manuscripts
    - American Presbyterians in British India - drafts, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 360)
    - Anglicans in Meerut - Rough draft, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 361)
    - Anglicans in Meerut - Final draft, 1970 Sept (Box 17, Folder 362)
    - Azariah of Dornakal - A play, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 363)
    - "Bible and Christian Social Action", in National Christian Council Review (1953) - reprint copy, 1953 Oct (Box 17, Folder 364)
    - Book on Devotions - includes letter by Mrs. Reinhold Niebuhr, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 365)
    - Christian Action in Society - draft, 1970 Feb (Box 17, Folder 366)
    - "Christian Study and Lay Training Centers" report published by Commission on Ecumenical Mission and Relations, United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. - published copy, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 367)
    - Christianity and British Rule in North India - draft, 1971 Mar (Box 17, Folder 368)
    - "Christianity, British Rule and the Challenge of Indian Nationalism", in Reflection (Christian Retreat and Study Centre, 1971/3), draft and published copy, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 369)
    - Christianity and Colonial Power - draft (Box 17, Folder 370)
    - Christianity and Communism - topical collected manuscripts (Box 17, Folder 371)
    - "Christianity in Uttar Pradesh: Prospectus of a study", in Reflection (Christian Retreat and Study Centre, 1975) - reprint copy (Box 17, Folder 372)
    - Christianity in Uttar Pradesh - rough draft, outline and introduction, 1982 Jan (Box 17, Folder 373)
    - Christianity in Uttar Pradesh - rough draft, chapter 1, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 374)
    - Christianity in Uttar Pradesh - final draft, chapter 1, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 375)
    - Christianity in Uttar Pradesh - rough draft, chapter 2, 1982 Nov (Box 17, Folder 376)
    - Christianity in Uttar Pradesh - final draft, chapter 2, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 377)
    - Christianity in Uttar Pradesh - rough draft, chapter 6, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 378)
    - Church of North India - draft, 1970 Dec (Box 17, Folder 379)
    - C.M.S. in Meerut 1858-1915 - draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 380)
    - Edwin Wallace Parker and the Beginnings of Indian Methodism, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 381)
    - Fellowship of Reconciliation - radio broadcast, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 382)
    - India and Pakistan: Issues behind Conflict and Indian and Pakistan at War, 1965, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 383)
    - India, Nation and Church - report, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 384)
    - Interview with Indonesia - draft and outline, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 385)
    - In the Doab and Rohilkhand - drafts and notes of JPA and son John Alter (Box 18, Folder 386)
    - "India Attempts Democracy", in Christianity and Crisis 9:13 (1951), drafts and published copy (Box 18, Folder 387)
    - Liberty, Equality, Fraternity - drafts, 1973 Oct (Box 18, Folder 388)
    - "Liberty, Equality, Fraternity", in Indian Church History Review 8:1 (1974), reprint copy, 1974 Jun (Box 18, Folder 389)
    - Methodists in Moradabad - rough draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 390)
    - Methodists in Moradabad - final draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 391)
    - Poor Amidst Plenty - partial draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 392)
    - Presbyterians in Farrukhabad - first draft, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 393)
    - Presbyterians in Farrukhabad - second draft, 1975 Mar (Box 18, Folder 394)
    - Presbyterians in Farrukhabad - final draft, 1975 Mar (Box 18, Folder 395)
    - "Presbyterians in Farrukhabad", in Indian Church History Review 9:2 and 10:1 (1975-1976), reprint copy (Box 19, Folder 396)
    - Presbyterians in Farrukhabad - later revisions by John Alter. Published by John Alter as "Half-way house: Presbyterians in Farrukhabad, 1838-1915" in Journal of Presbyterian History 62:3 (1984) (Box 19, Folder 397)
    - Resources for Worship - draft, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 398)
    - Revolution without Rupture, 1957 Dec (Box 19, Folder 399)
    - Some observations on the Yale Senior Societies, 1940 May (Box 19, Folder 400)
    - Strategy and tactics of Indian communism - drafts, 1951 May (Box 19, Folder 401)
    - World Council of Churches meets at Evanston, 1954 Jul (Box 19, Folder 402)
    - World Council of Churches - draft, 1955 Mar (Box 19, Folder 403)
    - miscellaneous and unidentified manuscripts (Box 19, Folder 404,405)
  - Student Papers
    - Analysis of Composite Situations - paper for Presbyterian polity course, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 406)
    - Contribution of Mysticism to Ethics - paper for H. Richard Niebuhr (includes comments from Niebuhr), 1942 (Box 19, Folder 407)
    - Platonic and Prophetic Conceptions of God - paper for Robert L. Calhoun (includes comments from Calhoun), 1940 Jun (Box 19, Folder 408)
    - miscellaneous student papers and exams, 1946-1951 (Box 19, Folder 409)
  - Book Reviews
    - Anglican Church in India by M. E. Gibbs. Published review in Indian Church History Review 7:2 (1973), 1973 Aug (Box 19, Folder 410)
    - Caesar the beloved enemy by M. A. C. Warren, 1956 May (Box 19, Folder 411)
    - Indian Working Class by Dr. Mukerjee, 1946 Oct (Box 19, Folder 412)
    - Paternalism and the Church by Michael Hallis, 1962 Oct (Box 19, Folder 413)
    - Christian Community and change in nineteenth century North India by John C. B. Webster. Published review in Indian Church History Review 10:2 (1976), 1976 Aug (Box 19, Folder 414)
    - "Christian Institute for the Study of Society" - bulletin, 1957 Aug (Box 19, Folder 415)
    - Church Faces the Challenge report by Church of Scotland Commission on Communism, 1955. (Box 19, Folder 416)
    - "Common Christian Responsibility" Issued by Department on Church and Society, World Council of Churches, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 417)
  - Sermons / Addresses
    - Addresses, 1938-1975 (Box 19, Folder 418-421)
    - Addresses, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 422)
    - Letter to Hindustan Times, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 423)
    - New Bethel Prayer Fellowship, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 424)
    - Sermons, 1946-1978 (Box 20, Folder 425-428)
    - Sermons and Prayers, Miscellaneous and undated (Box 20, Folder 429)
    - Worship materials, 1946-1950 (Box 20, Folder 430)
  - Lectures / Seminars
    - Course on British History, 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 431)
    - Lecture - Christian ministers and the study of history, 1973 Oct (Box 20, Folder 432)
    - Seminar - Living Hinduism, 1970 Jun (Box 20, Folder 433)
    - Seminar - Old Testament, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 434)
- Research Materials, Series III
  - Monographs/ Articles
    - A. F. Stone letter, 1817 (Box 21, Folder 435)
    - Allahabad Missionary Conferences, 1872-1873 (Box 21, Folder 436)
    - Article / letter by Charlotte Wiser, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 437)
    - Autobiographies, includes - Prakash Masih, Ganga Nath Shukul, Solomon Nihal Singh, and Zuhur-ul-Haqq (Box 21, Folder 438)
    - Benode Behari Roy, 1836-1927 (Box 21, Folder 439)
    - Calcutta Missionary Conferences, 1882-1883 (Box 21, Folder 440)
    - Dehra Dun's Girls School, 1891-1892 (Box 21, Folder 441)
    - "Evangelistic work in town and country", by C. H. Bundy, 1908 (Box 21, Folder 442)
    - "Forty Years in the C.M.S. by a convert from Hinduism" by Rev. Canon Solomon Nihal Singh, 1915 (Box 21, Folder 443)
    - Glance backward at fifteen years of missionary life in North India by Joseph Warren, 1856 (Box 21, Folder 444)
    - "Jesus as Social Reformer" author unknown, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 445)
    - Looking Back by Dr. J. J. Lucas, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 446)
    - Memorial Hospital, Fatehgarh -reports, 1859 (Box 21, Folder 447)
    - Memoirs of R. S. Fullerton and family. Includes editorial note by JPA and memoirs of Mrs. Leonard Waldo. (Box 21, Folder 448)
    - Memorial of the Futtehgurh Mission by J. J. Walsh, 1859 (Box 21, Folder 449)
    - "Methodists in Moradabad" - research materials, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 450)
    - "National Missionary Society of India" by Donald Fossett Ebright, 1944 Jun (Box 21, Folder 451)
    - North India Mission of Presbyterian Church - letters, 1857-1883 (Box 21, Folder 452)
    - North India Mission of Presbyterian Church - survey reports, 1943-1944 (Box 21, Folder 453)
    - North India Mission of Presbyterian Church - reports, 1885,1888, 1904,1906, 1924 (Box 21, Folder 454)
    - "Prayer" by J. H. Nichols and Radha Swami Sect by H. D. Griswold (Box 21, Folder 455)
    - Report of the North India Conference of Christian workers, 1905 (Box 21, Folder 456)
    - Samuel Henry Kellogg letter, 1864 (Box 21, Folder 457)
    - "Shakti Ashram" by Dr. Ernest Horrwitz, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 458)
    - "Theory and practice of the Christian Mission" bibliography (Box 21, Folder 459)
    - Tribes and castes of the North-Western provinces and Oudh by W. Crooke, 1896 (Box 22, Folder 460)
    - "Virtue in the Ramayana: the relationship between Dharma, Karma, and Artha" by Dismore Alter, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 461)
    - "Voices crying in the American wilderness," by David E. Swift, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 462)
    - "Worshipping Congregation and Worldly Christianity" by Hans Dietrich Wendland (Box 22, Folder 463)
    - Miscellaneous collected articles and manuscripts, 1942-1952 (Box 22, Folder 464)
  - Notes / Notebooks
    - American Presbyterians - notes, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 465)
    - Bible study notes, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 466)
    - Church of North India, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 467)
    - Class notes - Christian church in communist lands, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 468)
    - Class notes -Communist governments. Prof. Raymond, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 469)
    - Class notes -Christian interpretation of history, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 470)
    - Class notes -Jefferson School lectures, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 471)
    - Class notes -Marxist theory. Dr. Eduard Heimann, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 472)
    - Class notes -Social ethics in Protestant theology, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 473)
    - Class notes -workshops, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 474)
    - Class notes -miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 475)
    - Farrukhabad Study - notes, Outline, etc., 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 476)
    - Hindi grammar books (Box 23, Folder 477,478)
    - Hindi theological literature, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 479)
    - Missionary motives - notes and bibliography (Box 23, Folder 480)
    - Moradabad Study, 1971-1974 (Box 23, Folder 481)
    - Notes on various conversations - World Council of Churches Study Department, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 482)
    - Notes on conversations, includes - David Scott, P. N. Chopra, and Robert Holmes, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 483)
    - Notes - conversation on communism and Christianity at Dr. Bates house, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 484)
    - Notes - Delhi Churches, 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 485,486,487,488)
    - Notes - "Meerut", 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 489)
    - Notes - World Council of Churches study department, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 490)
    - Notecards - "British rule in India" (Box 24, Folder 491)
    - Notecards - "Census" and "History" (Box 24, Folder 492)
    - Notecards - Christianity in Uttar Pradesh, chapter 2, 1969-1973 (Box 24, Folder 493)
    - Notecards - General, 1969-1982 (Box 24, Folder 494,495,496)
    - Notecards - Lectures on theology to the natives in India, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 497)
    - Notecards - "Methodists", n.d. (Box 24, Folder 498)
    - Notecards - "Presbyterians", 1973 (Box 24, Folder 499)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Christians in India: Issues and Activities. Topics include: Christian churches and the Indian government; Social issues and caste system; Issues of religious freedom; Rights of Christians in India, 1946-1962 (Box 24, Folder 500)
    - Religious Issues in India. Topics include: Catholic and Orthodox churches in India; Indian cultures and religions; Religious conversions, 1960-1975 (Box 24, Folder 501)
    - News article, "Assignment: The Subcontinent - India", published in Harrison News Herald, Cadiz, Ohio in 1975, by Milton and Nately Ronsheim, Presbyterian missionaries to India.
- Collected Material, Series IV
  Folder labels in quotations are Alter's designations.
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1940-1943 (Box 25, Folder 502)
  - Association of Asian Studies, 1969-1971 (Box 25, Folder 503)
  - Bible Society in India and Ceylon: North India Auxiliary, 1947-1950 (Box 25, Folder 504)
  - "Calcutta", 1974 (Box 25, Folder 505)
  - Christian Institute for the Study of Religion and Society, Bangalore, India, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 506)
  - Christian fellowship groups, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 507)
  - "Christian Missionary in North India", 1948-1949 (Box 25, Folder 508)
  - Christian Retreat and Study Centre, Rajpur, India, 1958-1981 (Box 25, Folder 509)
  - "Christians in Meerut: A sociological study", 1976 (Box 25, Folder 510)
  - "Christianity and Communism" - collected documents (Box 25, Folder 511,512)
  - Church History Association of India, 1974-1976 (Box 25, Folder 513,514)
  - Church History Association of India - Conference, 1975 Oct (Box 25, Folder 515)
  - Church of North India - Inauguration, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 516,517)
  - "Conscription", 1944 (Box 26, Folder 518)
  - Course Material - Early and Medieval Church History. (Prof. Roland Bainton) (Box 26, Folder 519)
  - Course Material - European Church History.(Prof. Roland Bainton), 1940,1942 (Box 26, Folder 520)
  - Course Material - History of Christian Social Teaching. (Prof. Roland Bainton), 1945 (Box 26, Folder 521)
  - Course Material - History of Philosophy. (Prof. R. Calhoun), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 522)
  - Course Material - New Testament Interpretation. (Prof. Kraeling), 1942 (Box 26, Folder 523)
  - Course Material - Old Testament Interpretation. (Prof. N. Dahl), 1941-1942 (Box 26, Folder 524)
  - Course Material - miscellaneous, unidentified, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 525)
  - David Nelson Beach II - material, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 526)
  - Ecumenical Institute, Chateau de Bossey, Switzerland, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 527)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1935-1939 (Box 26, Folder 528)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 529-532)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1941-1948 (Box 27, Folder 533-543)
  - Fellowship of Socialist Christians, India, 1945-1947 (Box 28, Folder 544)
  - First Church of Christ, New Haven, CT, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 545)
  - Friends of the Soil, 1943 (Box 28, Folder 546)
  - India - Churches, 1946-1962 (Box 28, Folder 547)
  - India - Collected reports (Box 28, Folder 548)
  - India - Social and political documents, 1949-1968 (Box 28, Folder 549)
  - India Council Bulletin, 1945-1948 (Box 28, Folder 550)
  - India - Pakistan - Bangladesh conflicts, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 551)
  - India - United Church of North India - surveys, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 552)
  - India - United Church of North India Synod: Articles and Reports, 1963-1965 (Box 28, Folder 553)
  - Indonesia - Church and society documents, 1968-1973 (Box 28, Folder 554,555)
  - Institute for Propaganda Analysis, 1941 (Box 28, Folder 556)
  - Interseminary Movement in U.S., 1945-1947 (Box 28, Folder 557)
  - "Landour", 1946-1951 (Box 28, Folder 558)
  - Leonard Theological College, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 559)
  - Leonard Theological College - Educational Policy Conference, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 560,561)
  - Letter and newssheet by D. Emmett Alter, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 562)
  - Methodist Church in South Asia, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 563)
  - National Committee on Food for Small Democracies, 1941 (Box 29, Folder 564)
  - National Intercollegiate Christian Council, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 565)
  - National Intercollegiate Christian Council, 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 566,567)
  - Newark Christian Colony, 1941 (Box 29, Folder 568)
  - Northfield - Mount Hermon School, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 569)
  - North India Synod, 1956-1980 (Box 29, Folder 570)
  - Pakistan - "Church and Nation", 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 571)
  - Peace Fellowship of the Presbyterian Church, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 572)
  - Peace Organizations - includes: American Friends Service Committee; Commission on World Peace, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 573)
  - Presbyterian Church in U.S.A. - Board of Foreign Missions, 1942-1945 (Box 29, Folder 574,575)
  - Presbyterian Church in U.S.A. - Foreign Missions and Overseas Interchurch Service, 1951-1952 (Box 29, Folder 576)
  - Saint Andrew's Girls' School, Jeyi, India, 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 577)
  - Sermons, Addresses, Worship Materials, 1945-1979 (Box 29, Folder 578)
  - Southern Tenant Farmers Union, 1940 (Box 29, Folder 579)
  - Student Christian Movement in New England, 1938-1939 (Box 29, Folder 580-581)
  - Student Christian Movement in New England, 1940-1942 (Box 30, Folder 582-584)
  - Student peace groups. Includes - Student Peace Service; Youth Committee Against War; Keep America Out of War Congress; Peace Volunteer Fellowship, 1938-1941 (Box 30, Folder 585,586,587,588)
  - Student Volunteer Movement, 1941-1943 (Box 30, Folder 589-590)
  - Student Volunteer Movement - Wooster Conference, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 591)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Commission on Ecumenical Mission and Relations, 1964-1973 (Box 31, Folder 592)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Community and Mission Consultation, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 593)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Home Assignment Conference, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 594)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Missionary Guidelines, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 595)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Missionary Handbook, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 596)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Personal Interest Program, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 597)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Personal Development Interviews, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 598)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Program Agency: Conference on Mission, Lake Forest College, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 599,600,601)
  - United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A.: Retired Missionaries Service, 1977-1978 (Box 31, Folder 602)
  - Woodstock School, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 603)
  - World Council of Churches: Study Department: Christianity and Communism, 1950, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 604,605)
  - World Council of Churches: Evanston Assembly, Articles, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 606)
  - World Council of Churches: International Missionary Council, Ghana Assembly, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 607)
  - World Council of Churches: Third Assembly, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 608,609)
  - World Council of Churches: Womens Consultation, New Delhi, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 610)
  - World Council of Churches: miscellaneous documents (Box 32, Folder 611)
  - World Pacifist Meeting, 1947-1949 (Box 32, Folder 612)
  - World Student Christian Federation, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 613)
  - Yale University Christian Association, 1942-1974 (Box 32, Folder 614)
  - Yale Divinity School - Alumni Newsletter, Class 1952, 1962-1983 (Box 32, Folder 615,616)
  - Yale Divinity School - Student Evaluation, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 617)
  - Young Peoples Socialist League, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 618)
  - "Yugoslavia", 19501-951 (Box 32, Folder 619)
  - miscellaneous collected material, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 620)
- Biographical Material, Series V
  - Photographs of missionary groups in India, 1922, 1925, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 621)
  - Haydenburg, Tennessee. Work of JPA at New Bethel Church under auspices of Presbyterian Board of National Missions. Sample documentation; see also: Series I, General correspondence, Haydenburg, Tennessee., 1942-1944 (Box 33, Folder 622)
  - Annual medical examinations, 1943-1979 (Box 33, Folder 623)
  - Diplomas, certificates: James Alter, Board of Foreign Missions, 1945; James Alter, Leonard Theological College, 1947; Barbara Alter, Board of Foreign Missions, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 624)
  - Leonard Theological College, Photographs, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 625)
  - Passports, JPA and BBA, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 626)
  - East Asia Trip, Transcript notes, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 627)
  - Travel diary, Africa and Far East, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 628)
  - Dehra Dun, Administrative concerns, 1959-1963 (Box 33, Folder 629)
  - East Asia Trip, Transcript notes, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 630)
  - Punjab Trip, notes, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 631)
  - Trip to California, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 632)
  - Nature diary, Rajpur, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 633)
  - Travel diary, South India and Ceylon, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 634)
  - Study project, Lodhiana, 1967-1970 (Box 33, Folder 635)
  - Study project, USA, 1967-1970 (Box 33, Folder 636)
  - Trip to California, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 637)
  - Study projects, "consultants", 1968-1973 (Box 33, Folder 638)
  - Progress reports on Study of North India for the Presbyterian Church, 1968-1974 (Box 33, Folder 639)
  - Profiles, Interviews and Reports by JPA and BBA for the United Presbyterian Church in U.S.A. Includes photographs of JPA and BBA, 1968-1975 (Box 33, Folder 640)
  - Study project, John Webster, 1968-1975 (Box 33, Folder 641)
  - Alter, Beach family history, 1968-1978 (Box 33, Folder 642)
  - Dismore Alter, biographical information, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 643)
  - Notes on various conversations, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 644)
  - Kentucky - Tennessee Trip, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 645)
  - Study projects, COEMAR, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 646)
  - Study project, Delhi, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 647)
  - Travel, U.S., London, India, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 648)
  - Corning, NY news clipping and photograph of Alters, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 649)
  - Study project, United Kingdom, 1969-1970 (Box 34, Folder 650)
  - Study project, Meerut, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 651)
  - Study project, India, 1969-1976 (Box 34, Folder 652)
  - Trip to Dacca, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 653)
  - Family reunions, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 654)
  - Study projects, U.S.A., 1972 (Box 34, Folder 655)
  - Study projects, miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 656)
  - Study projects, U.S.A., accounts, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 657)
  - Personal Reports, United Presbyterian Church, 1972-1977 (Box 34, Folder 658)
  - Travel itineraries, 1972-1979 (Box 34, Folder 659)
  - Study project, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 660)
  - Travel, Australia and New Zealand, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 661)
  - Study Project, Travel to Indonesia, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 662)
  - James Alter, caricature by Roland H. Bainton, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 663)
  - Indonesia, reports and correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 664)